[
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has a complete blockage of airflow then sudden release?",
    "answer": "stop",
    "otherOptions": "fricative_nasal_liquid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has a continuous but constricted airflow through the mouth?",
    "answer": "fricative",
    "otherOptions": "stop_nasal_approximant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has the articulators very close together but not touching?",
    "answer": "fricative",
    "otherOptions": "plosive_glide_nasal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has a complete blockage of airflow then a slow release?",
    "answer": "affricate",
    "otherOptions": "stop_approximant_tap"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has the tip of tongue rapidly contact the roof the mouth once?",
    "answer": "tap",
    "otherOptions": "stop_fricative_affricate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation can have either oral or nasal airflow?",
    "answer": "plosive",
    "otherOptions": "fricative_flap_glide"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Hz and the first formant is high, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "low",
    "otherOptions": "high"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Hz and the first formant is low, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "high",
    "otherOptions": "low"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Hz and the second formant is high, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "front",
    "otherOptions": "back"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Hz and the second formant is low, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "back",
    "otherOptions": "front"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Bark and the first formant is high, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "high",
    "otherOptions": "low"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Bark and the first formant is low, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "low",
    "otherOptions": "high"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Bark and the second formant is high, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "back",
    "otherOptions": "front"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a spectrogram is in Bark and the second formant is low, what type of vowel does that indicate?",
    "answer": "front",
    "otherOptions": "back"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation doesn’t have formants?",
    "answer": "fricatives",
    "otherOptions": "plosives_nasals_approximants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manner of articulation has one formant and one 'anti-formant'?",
    "answer": "nasals",
    "otherOptions": "plosives_fricatives_approximants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which approximants are distinguished by their 1st and 2nd formants?",
    "answer": "glides",
    "otherOptions": "liquids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which approximants rae distinguished by their 2nd and 3rd formants?",
    "answer": "liquids",
    "otherOptions": "glides"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the voice onset time (VOT) for voiced consonants?",
    "answer": "< 0 ms",
    "otherOptions": "0 - 35 ms_35+ ms"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the voice onset time (VOT) for voiceless unaspirated consonants?",
    "answer": "0 - 35 ms",
    "otherOptions": "< 0 ms_35+ ms"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the voice onset time (VOT) for voiceless plain consonants?",
    "answer": "0 - 35 ms",
    "otherOptions": "< 0 ms_35+ ms"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the voice onset time (VOT) for voiceless aspirated consonants?",
    "answer": "35+ ms",
    "otherOptions": "< 0 ms_0 - 35 ms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which voicing is also called ‘prevoiced’?",
    "answer": "voiced",
    "otherOptions": "voiceless plain_voiceless aspirated"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which voicing is also called ‘short lag’?",
    "answer": "voiceless plain",
    "otherOptions": "voiced_voiceless aspirated"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which voicing is also called ‘long lag’?",
    "answer": "voiceless aspirated",
    "otherOptions": "voiced_voiceless plain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature does not help identify plosives in a spectrogram?",
    "answer": "amplitude",
    "otherOptions": "duration_VOT_voicing band"
  },
  {
    "question": "Low vowels are inherently shorter than high vowels.",
    "answer": "false",
    "otherOptions": "true"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a spectrogram, affricates look like noisy stops.",
    "answer": "true",
    "otherOptions": "false"
  },
  {
    "question": "[h] & [ʔ] pattern sometimes as obstruents and sometimes as sonorants.",
    "answer": "true",
    "otherOptions": "false"
  },
  {
    "question": "Liquids are also called semivowels, and appear as exaggerated vowels in a spectrogram.",
    "answer": "false",
    "otherOptions": "true"
  }
]